Register of the Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, 1914-1930
Hoover Institution Archives
- CHAIRMAN'S FILE, 1914-1924
  - Correspondence
    - Galpin, Perrin C., 1914-1916 (Folder 43)
    - Gay, Edwin F., 1918 (Folder 44)
    - Gerard, James W., 1915 (Folder 45)
    - Gibson, Hugh S., 1915-1918 (Folder 46)
    - Goltz, Von der, 1914 (Folder 47)
    - Goode, William, 1914-1919 (Folder 48)
    - Gray, Prentiss, 1917-1921 (Folder 49)
    - Honnold, W. L., 1917 (Folder 50)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1916-1918 (Folder 51)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry, 1923 (Folder 52)
    - House, E. M., 1917 (Folder 53)
    - Hurley, Edward J., 1917 (Folder 54)
    - Jagow, Von Herr, 1915 (Folder 55)
    - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1917 (Folder 56)
    - Kelley, N., 1920 (Folder 57)
    - Kellogg, Mrs., 1915-1924 (Folder 58)
    - Kessler, Von, 1916 (Folder 59)
    - Kneass, Edward D., 1919 (Folder 60)
    - Lancken, Von der, 1916 (Folder 61)
    - Level, M. E., 1917 (Folder 62)
    - Lindley, Josephine, 1914 (Folder 63)
    - Listoe, S., 1918 (Folder 64)
    - McGowan, J. J., 1917 (Folder 65)
    - Mey, C. F. De, 1914 (Folder 66)
    - Michaels, C. F., 1915 (Folder 67)
    - Moreira, Alberto de Ipanema, 1917 (Folder 68)
    - Murdock, Donald, Mrs., 1915 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Nansen, Fridjof, 1917 (Folder 2)
    - Osborne, D. G., 1917 (Folder 3)
    - Page, W. H., 1914 (Folder 4)
    - Percy, Eustace, 1916-1917 (Folder 5)
    - Phillips, William, 1917 (Folder 6)
    - Poland, William B., 1916-1917 (Folder 7)
    - Polk, Frank L., 1917 (Folder 8)
    - Rappard, W. L. F. C. Van, 1917 (Folder 9)
    - Reading? 1919 (Folder 10)
    - Rickard, Edgar, 1917-1919 (Folder 11)
    - Royce, Ruth, 1914 (Folder 12)
    - Ruddock, A. B., 1915 (Folder 13)
    - Ryan, Harris J., Mr. and Mrs., 1915 (Folder 14)
    - San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 1914 (Folder 15)
    - Shepardson, Whitney, 1917 (Folder 16)
    - Sherman, Roger, 1918-1920 (Folder 17)
    - Simpson, John L., 1918 (Folder 18)
    - Smith, W. H., 1914 (Folder 19)
    - Tumulty, J. P., 1917 (Folder 20)
    - United States. Food Administration, 1918 (Folder 21)
    - United States. Purchasing Commission, n.d. (Folder 22)
    - United States. Secretary of the Treasury (Folder 23)
    - United States. Shipping Board, 1917 (Folder 24)
    - Van Duzer, Frederick C., 1918 (Folder 25)
    - Vyver, A. van der, 1917 (Folder 26)
    - Waele, L. De, 1917 (Folder 27)
    - Wiart, Edmond Carton de, 1918 (Folder 28)
    - Wiggins, Frank, 1914 (Folder 29)
    - Wilbur, Mrs.? 1915 (Folder 30)
    - Williams, Edward J., Mrs., 1921 (Folder 31)
    - Wilson, J. E. Mrs., 1914 (Folder 32)
    - Wilson, Woodrow, 1917-1918 (Folder 33)
    - Windslow, L. Lanier, 1915 (Folder 34)
    - Woodward, F. C., 1915 (Folder 35)
    - World's Work, 1914 (Folder 36)
    - Wythbeoeck, Marguerite, 1914 (Folder 37)
  - Decree for the occupied territory of Belgium (Folder 38)
  - Deposition, American Consulate, Liverpool, Great Britain (Folder 39)
  - Financial records. Includes letters and memoranda by Herbert Hoover on the financial co-operation between the United States and Europe (Folder 40)
  - Interviews with Ambassador Page, Colonel House and Eustace Percy (Folder 41)
  - Memoranda (Folder 42)
  - Minutes of meetings (Folder 43)
  - Notes (Folder 44)
  - Outline. Includes the duties and activities of a provincial representative of the C.R.B. (Folder 45)
  - Passes and passport file of Herbert Hoover (Folder 46)
  - Press release issued by the United States Food Administration on matters of general policy (Folder 47)
  - Printed matter (Folder 48)
  - Record of daily events (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Remarks. Includes remarks made by Edward Grey, British Foreign Minister, in the House of Commons on the C.R.B. and the Belgian question; David F. Houston, American Secretary of Agriculture, and others (Folder 2)
  - Reports (Folder 3-4)
  - Statements. Includes miscellaneous statements and drafts made by Herbert Hoover during his visit to the United States in early 1917 (Folder 5-6)
  - Statistical records (Folder 7)
  - Telegrams (Folder 8)
  - Miscellany (Folder 9)
- EXECUTIVE ALPHABETICAL FILE, 1912-1942
  Includes cables, correspondence, dossiers, inter-office communication, list of supplies, memoranda, minutes of meetings, telegrams, and travel records
  - Balbour, A. J. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baetens, Fernand (Folder 2)
  - Bates, Lindon W. (Folder 3-9)
  - Bates, Lindon W. (Box 10, Folder 1-18)
  - Bliss, Taskar, W.? (Folder 19)
  - Brown, Walter Lyman (Folder 20-23)
  - Brown, Walter Lyman (Box 11, Folder 1-12)
  - Cambon, Paul (Folder 13)
  - Carlin, Gaston M. (Folder 14)
  - Chalmers, William J (Folder 15-18)
  - Chevrillon, L. (Folder 19-22)
  - Chevrillon, L. (Box 12, Folder 1-15)
  - Crosby, Oscar T. (Folder 16-17)
  - Francqui, Emile (Box 13-14)
  - Galpin, Perrin C. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Gay, G. I. (Folder 2-9)
  - Gay, G. I. (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
  - Gerard, James W. (Folder 4)
  - Gibson, Hugh (Folder 5-15)
  - Goode, William (Folder 16-17)
  - Goode, William (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Gray, Prentiss N. (Folder 4-10)
  - Grey, Edward (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Herter, Christian A. (Folder 2)
  - Honnold, William H. (Folder 3-9)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. Includes documents concerning the formation of the C.R.B. in Box 19 and correspondence between Woodrow Wilson, President of the United States, and King Albert of Belgium, in Box 26 (Box 19-30)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
  - House, E. M. (Folder 4)
  - Hunsiker, Millard (Folder 5-7)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (Folder 8-9)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
  - Lalaing, Count de (Folder 5)
  - Lansing, Robert (Folder 6)
  - Lloyd George, David (Folder 7)
  - Lucey, J. F. (Folder 8-9)
  - McAdoo, W. G. (Folder 10)
  - Moncheur, Baron (Folder 11)
  - Page, Walter Hines (Folder 12)
  - Percy, Eustace (Folder 13)
  - Pinchot, Gifford (Folder 14)
  - Poland, W. B. (Folder 15-16)
  - Poland, W. B. (Box 33-39)
  - Ramaix, G. de (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Richards, Lewis (Folder 2-7)
  - Richards, Lewis (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 5-7)
  - Rickard, Edgar (Box 42, Folder 1-8)
  - Rickard, Edgar (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Folder 3)
  - Shaler, Millard K. (Folder 4-6)
  - Shaler, Millard K. (Box 44, Folder 1-7)
  - Sharp, William G. (Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Lewis (Folder 9)
  - Tuck, William Hallam (Folder 10)
  - Val, Merry del (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Van Dyke, Henry (Folder 2)
  - Villalobar, Marquis de (Folder 3)
  - War Refugee Committee (Folder 4)
  - War Victims Relief Committee of the Society of Friends (Folder 5)
  - White, John Beaver (Folder 6-9)
  - Whitlock, Brand, Mrs. (Folder 10)
  - Wiart, Carton de (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Folder 5)
- EXECUTIVE CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1914-1919
  Booklets, cables, charts, clippings, correspondence, deposition, notes, inter-office communication, loading schedule, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, outline of plan, printed matter, programs of monthly imports, reports, statistical records, speeches, statements, and telegrams
  - 1914 October-December (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
  - 1915 (Box 48)
    - January-March 15 (Folder 1-4)
    - March 16-June (Box 49, Folder 1-7)
    - July-December 20 (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
    - December 22-31 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - 1916
    - General (Folder 2)
    - January-June 19 (Folder 3-9)
    - June 20-October 20 (Box 52, Folder 1-8)
    - October 21-December 20 (Box 53, Folder 1-6)
    - December 21-31 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - 1917
    - January-February 14 (Folder 2-4)
    - February 15-April (Box 55, Folder 1-5)
    - May-August (Box 56, Folder 1-5)
    - September-November (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - December (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - 1918
    - January-February (Folder 3-4)
    - March-July (Box 59, Folder 1-5)
    - August-November (Box 60, Folder 1-4)
    - December (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
  - 1919
    - January-May (Folder 3-7)
    - June-December (Box 62, Folder 1-7)
- EXECUTIVE GEOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1914-1922.
  Bulletins, cables, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, messages, minutes of meetings and conferences, notes, printed matter, reports, speeches, statements, telegrams, and testimony
  - Belgium (Box 63)
    - External affairs
      - Argentina (Folder 1)
      - France (Folder 2)
      - Great Britain (Folder 3-5)
      - Great Britain (Box 64, Folder 1-6)
      - Netherlands (Folder 7-8)
      - United States (Folder 9-12)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 13)
    - Internal affairs (Box 65)
      - King Albert. Includes the cable sent by the President of the United States, Woodrow Wilson, to King Albert of Belgium (Folder 1)
      - Ministry of Finance (Folder 2-5)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 6)
      - Ministry of Industry (Folder 7)
      - Ministry of Interior (Folder 8)
      - Ministry of Marine, Post, Telegraph (Folder 9-10)
      - Ministry of Marine, Post, Telegraph (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
      - Ministry 0f Transport - Marines (Folder 5)
      - Ministry of Reconstruction (Folder 6)
      - Ministry of War Defense (Folder 7)
      - Prime Minister (Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 9)
  - France
    - External affairs
      - Great Britain (Folder 10-12)
      - Great Britain (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
      - Netherlands (Folder 3)
      - United States (Folder 4-5)
    - Internal affairs
      - Liaison Offices (Folder 6)
      - Ministry of Blockade of Liberated Regions (Folder 7)
      - Ministry of Commerce (Folder 8)
      - Ministry of Finance (Folder 9)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 10-11)
      - Ministry of Interior (Folder 12)
      - Ministry of Public Works (Folder 13)
      - Ministry of Ravitaillement (Folder 14)
      - Ministry of War (Folder 15)
      - President (Folder 16)
  - Germany
    - External affairs - Consular offices and Legations (Folder 17)
    - Internal affairs relating to Foreign Office (Folder 18)
    - Occupation of Belgium and Northern France (Folder 19-21)
    - Occupation of Belgium and Northern France (Box 68, Folder 1-4)
    - Occupation of Belgium and Northern France (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
  - Great Britain
    - External affairs
      - General (Folder 4)
      - France (Folder 5)
      - Netherlands (Folder 6)
      - Netherlands (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - United States (Folder 2)
    - Internal affairs
      - General - Chronology (Folder 3)
      - Foreign Office (Folder 4-9)
      - Foreign Office (Box 71, Folder 1-7)
      - Foreign Office (Box 72, Folder 1-8)
      - Foreign Office (Box 73, Folder 1-10)
      - Ministry of Food (Folder 11)
      - Prime Minister (Folder 12)
      - Secretary of State (Folder 13-14)
      - Secretary of State (Box 74, Folder 1-3)
      - Treasury (Folder 4)
  - Spain
    - External Affairs
      - Belgium (Folder 5)
      - Germany (Folder 6)
      - Great Britain (Folder 7-10)
      - Great Britain (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Netherlands (Folder 2)
    - Internal affairs (Folder 3)
  - Switzerland
    - External affairs
      - Great Britain (Folder 4-5)
      - United States (Folder 6)
    - Internal affairs relating to Foreign Office (Folder 7)
  - United States
    - External affairs
      - General - Consular affairs (Folder 8)
      - Argentina (Folder 9)
      - Belgium (Folder 10-11)
      - Belgium (Box 76, Folder 1-4)
      - Belgium (Box 77, Folder 1-4)
      - Bulgaria (Folder 5)
      - Denmark (Folder 6)
      - France (Folder 7-8)
      - Germany (Folder 9)
      - Germany (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
      - Great Britain (Folder 3-8)
      - Great Britain (Box 79, Folder 1-8)
      - Great Britain (Box 80, Folder 1-8)
      - Great Britain (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
      - Italy (Folder 3)
      - Netherlands (Folder 4-10)
      - Norway (Folder 11)
      - Poland (Folder 12)
      - Russia (Folder 13)
      - Serbia (Folder 14)
      - Spain (Folder 15)
      - Sweden (Folder 16)
      - Switzerland (Folder 17)
    - Internal affairs (Box 82)
      - General - Departments and commissions (Folder 1)
      - Department of Interior (Folder 2)
      - Department of Navy (Folder 3)
      - Department of State (Folder 4-8)
      - Department of Treasury (Folder 9)
      - Department of War (Folder 10)
      - President (Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous countries
    - Argentina (Folder 12)
    - Armenia (Folder 13)
    - Austria (Folder 14)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 15)
    - Chile (Folder 16)
    - Cuba (Folder 17)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 18)
    - Greece (Folder 19)
    - Holland (Folder 20)
    - Italy (Folder 21)
    - Luxemburg (Folder 22)
    - Netherlands (Folder 23)
    - Netherlands (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Norway (Folder 2-3)
    - Poland (Folder 4-6)
    - Romania (Folder 7)
    - Russia (Folder 8)
    - Serbia (Folder 9-10)
    - Sweden (Folder 11-12)
- BRUSSELS OFFICE FILE, 1914-1919
  Allotting schedule, clippings, correspondence, inter-office communication, lists of merchandise, memoranda, note, printed matter, reports, shipping agreements, statements, and telegrams
  - General (Box 84)
    - General. Includes records relating to conditions in Belgium, guarantees and undertakings from German authorities, misuse of food by the Germans, and to the supply and distribution of sugar (Folder 1-4)
    - 1914 (Folder 5)
    - 1915 January-December (Folder 6-7)
    - 1916
      - January-September (Folder 8-9)
      - October-December (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - 1917 January-December (Folder 2-3)
    - 1918
      - January-June (Folder 4)
      - July-December (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - 1919 January-October (Folder 2)
    - 1918-1919 (Folder 3-4)
  - Department of Inspection and Control
    - General. Includes records relating to the needs for, and composition and distribution of, soups, and to foodstuff in general (Folder 5-7)
    - Commercial exchange lists (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Dossier of Joseph C. Green, Chief of the Department. Includes letters sent out mostly to American Provincial representatives regarding matters of procedure and infraction of guarantees (Folder 2-3)
    - Infraction of guarantees records (Folder 4)
    - List of questionnaires (Folder 5)
    - Organizational structure and description of duties (Folder 6-7)
    - Record of the investigation into the condition of the people of Belgium (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Reports. Includes records relating to the abuses prior to the organization of the Department and to the activities of the clothing department of the National Committee
      - General (Folder 2-4)
        - 1916
          - February (Folder 5)
          - March (Folder 6-7)
          - April-May (Folder 8-10)
          - June (Box 89, Folder 1)
          - July (Folder 2)
          - August (Folder 3)
          - September (Folder 4-5)
          - September-October (Box 90, Folder 1)
          - October (Folder 2-4)
          - November (Folder 5-6)
          - December (Folder 7)
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 8)
        - 1917 (Box 91)
          - January (Folder 1)
          - January-March (Folder 2)
          - March-April (Folder 3)
      - Export of fertilisers (Folder 4)
      - Internal transport system in Belgium (Folder 5-8)
      - Provincial Committee of the Department
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Brabant (Box 92, Folder 1)
        - Hainaut (Folder 2-3)
        - Liege (Folder 4)
        - Limburg (Folder 5)
        - Luxemburg (Folder 6)
        - Mamur (Folder 7)
  - Telegrams (Folder 8)
- LILLE OFFICE FILE, 1919
  - General (Box 93)
    - Correspondence, March-July (Folder 1)
    - Lists
      - Communes (Folder 2)
      - Medicines (Folder 3)
      - Memoranda (Folder 4)
  - Department of Child Welfare
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Chart (Folder 6)
    - Clipping (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, April-June (Folder 8)
    - List of medical supplies (Folder 9)
    - Medical invoices (Folder 10)
    - Memoranda (Folder 11)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 12)
    - Notes (Folder 13)
    - Personnel records (Folder 14)
    - Records authorizing the loan of nurses from the American Red Cross to the C.R.B. (Folder 15)
    - Reports. Includes reports on conditions in Belgium for children and on increased food rations necessary for them in Belgium and Northern France (Folder 16)
- LONDON OFFICE ACCOUNTS FILE, 1915-1920
  - Automobile expense record (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Balance sheets, reports, sundry statements, and trial balances (Folder 2-4)
  - Balance sheets. Includes trial balances and statements and balance sheets from Rotterdam Office (Box 95, Folder 1-3)
  - Bank balance statements (Folder 4)
  - Bankbooks (Box 96)
  - Commercial exchange account logs (Box 97-102)
  - Commercial exchange account logs (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence (Folder 3-4)
  - List of donations (Folder 5)
  - List of goods despatched and received (Folder 6)
  - List of goods despatched and received (Box 104, Folder 1-2)
  - Minutes of meetings. Includes records of subscriptions received (Folder 3)
  - Orders and delivery schedule. Includes correspondence, invoices and telegrams
    - Argentina (Folder 4)
    - Belgium. Includes material relating to the amount of rations to be delivered to the Belgians for the relief of civilians in evacuated territory, and the offers and invoices for the supply of hospital cloth
      - General (Folder 5-7)
      - General (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - 1917-1919 (Folder 2-10)
      - 1918-1919 (Box 106, Folder 1-4)
    - Great Britain. Includes list of miscellaneous shipments from various ports in Great Britain and invoices for wheat supply and others
      - General (Folder 5-6)
      - 1917 (Folder 7)
      - 1917-1918 (Box 107, Folder 1-2)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 3-6)
      - 1918-1920 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - 1919 (Folder 2-3)
    - Northern France
      - General
        - 1917 (Folder 4-8)
        - 1917-1918 (Box 109, Folder 1-5)
        - 1918 (Folder 6)
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
      - Financial reports (Folder 8)
  - Reconciliation statements (Box 110, Folder 1-2)
  - Record of sales and foodstuff supplied to Germany (Folder 3-5)
  - Statements of claims received from the Ministry of Food, London (Folder 6-7)
  - Summary of shipments to Belgium, Northern France and other destinations (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Booklet (Folder 2)
    - Clippings (Folder 3)
    - Financial records
      - General (Folder 4-7)
      - General (Box 112, Folder 1-7)
      - General (Box 113, Folder 1-2)
      - Duplicate invoices from the Rotterdam Office (Folder 3)
      - Records from the New York Office (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter (Folder 5)
    - Receipes (Folder 6)
- LONDON OFFICE GENERAL FILE, 1914-1920
  - Cables and telegrams (Box 114)
    - New York Office
      - 1914 October-1915 January (Folder 1)
      - 1915
        - February-March (Folder 2)
        - April-July (Folder 3)
        - July-November (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - 1915 December-1916 March (Folder 2)
      - 1916
        - April-July (Folder 3)
        - August-October (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - 1916 November-1917 January (Folder 2)
      - 1917
        - February-April (Folder 3-4)
        - May-July (Box 117, Folder 1)
        - August-October (Folder 2)
      - 1917 November-1918 January (Folder 3)
      - 1918
        - February-April (Folder 4)
        - May-July (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - August-November (Folder 2)
      - 1918 November-1919 March (Folder 3)
      - 1919 April-August (Folder 4)
  - Clippings (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Includes charts and tables, invoices, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, statements, statistical bulletins and telegrams
    - General
      - 1914 October-December (Folder 2)
      - 1915
        - May (Folder 3)
        - June-July (Folder 4)
        - August-October (Folder 5)
        - November-December (Folder 6)
      - 1916 (Box 120)
        - January (Folder 1)
        - February-March (Folder 2)
        - April-May (Folder 3)
        - June-July (Folder 4-5)
        - August-December (Box 121, Folder 1-5)
      - 1917 (Box 122)
        - January-February (Folder 1-2)
        - March-June (Folder 3-6)
        - July-December (Box 123, Folder 1-6)
      - 1918 January-December (Box 124, Folder 1-12)
      - 1919 January-December (Box 125, Folder 1-5)
    - Raymond, Pynchon and Company (Folder 6)
    - Spyer, Edmund (Folder 7)
    - Wylie, F. J. (Folder 8)
  - Directory of Belgian supervisors (Folder 9-10)
  - Financial records
    - Banque Belge
      - 1914-1915 (Folder 11)
      - 1916 (Folder 12)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 13)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 14)
    - C.R.B. Accounts Department, 1919 (Folder 15)
  - German coal claim records (Folder 16)
  - Lists (Box 126)
    - C.R.B. recipients of Comité National de Secours et d'Alimentation medal (Folder 1)
    - Duties of American representatives in the provinces (Folder 2)
  - Memoranda (Folder 3)
  - Population records for various provinces in Belgium and Northern France (Folder 4)
  - Reports. Includes correspondence, notes, statements
    - Undated (Folder 5)
    - 1914 (Folder 6)
    - 1914-1917 (Folder 7)
    - 1915. Includes reports by representatives in various provinces (Folder 8)
    - 1916. Includes Philip S. Pratt's report on a social, economic and dietetic study of twenty-seven working class families in the Province of Liège; and a report by William Palmer Lucas (Folder 9-12)
    - 1916-1918. The Fleskens Committee report (Folder 13)
    - 1917-1918 (Folder 14)
  - Shipping records (Folder 15-16)
  - Shipping records (Box 127, Folder 1-4)
  - Subject file. Includes articles, cables, clippings, correspondence, notes, outlines of plan, petitions, printed matter, reports, statements, and telegrams
    - American Red Cross (Folder 5)
    - American Relief Clearing House (Folder 6-7)
    - Belgian Orphan Fund (Folder 8)
    - Belgian Orphan Fund (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Central Prisoners of War Committee (Folder 2)
    - Commission Hispano- Americaine (Folder 3)
    - Commission Internationale de Ravitaillement (Folder 4)
    - Poland. Includes notes and a report prepared by Vernon Kellogg (Folder 5-15)
    - Wheat. Memorandum on the world situation (Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 17-18)
- LONDON OFFICE LACE DEPARTMENT FILE, 1915-1920
  - Booklet (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Includes some financial records
    - General
      - 1915-1919 (Folder 2)
      - 1917 (Folder 3)
      - 1917-1919 (Folder 4)
      - 1918 (Folder 5)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
      - 1919 (Folder 7)
    - Richards, Lewis (Folder 8)
    - Whitlock, Brand, Mrs. (Folder 9)
  - Financial records. Includes some correspondence
    - General. Includes C.R.B. records relating to the work in progress, audit schedule for wholesale and retail dealers, vouchers for payment, records of the Comité National de Secours et d'Alimentation, and some miscellaneous papers
      - General (Folder 10-11)
      - General (Box 130, Folder 1-3)
      - 1915-1920 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1916-1918 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
      - 1919-1920 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Bank books (Folder 2)
    - Cables relating to purchase of ships (Folder 3)
    - Cash books (Folder 4)
    - Cash books (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Check books (Folder 2)
    - Insurance (Folder 3)
    - Inventory (Folder 4)
    - Invoices (Box 133, Folder 1-2)
    - Journal (Folder 3-5)
    - Journal (Box 134, Folder 1-2)
    - Ledger (Folder 3-4)
    - Lists (Box 135)
      - Cargoes afloat and value of stocks (Folder 1)
      - Deliveries (Folder 2)
      - Ships and steamers (Folder 3-6)
    - Memoranda on handling account of the retail lace shop (Folder 7)
    - Receipts for various purchases, rent, repairs, and settlement of claims (Folder 8)
    - Receipts for various purchases, rent, repairs, and settlement of claims (Box 136, Folder 1-4)
    - Sales in transit (Folder 5)
    - Statements
      - Claims received from the British Ministry of Shipping (Folder 6-7)